so still in Hyde Park this is a chap who
I've met a few times down here known
only to me is my friend he is probably
the freest man I think that I know and
has the balls to actually live his life
pretty much entirely independently of
the Machine anyway he's the reason I've
got him on camera here is that he talked
to me a few weeks ago about an
alternative city design Venus Project is
something that you will see frequently
on my on my channel but this is a
similar kind of philosophy but an
entirely different design idea based on
a pyramidal shape and using hemp both as
a purifier of air and water and as a
building material anyway so I'll pass
over to my friend here who will tell you
more about it seems to be put a slight
problem with our carbon footprint we've
been digging up fossil fuels for
Ricki body from the ends
of millions of tons of carbon that we
get reduced to our atmosphere is
starting to weigh on us that where life
is going to run away project
that only as far as I'm aware the only
viable solutions to fix the carbon it's
it's beneficial to the best way
apparently as far as other we're fixing
that much carbon
grow lots lots of them
and produces the seed which will give us
oil and proteins
and it reduces resins in its stalks and
fibers Plastics growing it sheds its
leaves on the ground which fertilize the
soil and the roots in the soil off the
soil together so when we harvest it
leave the roots in the ground and they
will rot down in their own time take the
stalks stripped of apartment apply this
adventures past the
hoping the material in the middle
perfect accomplice
by fixing or by growing enough him we
need to grow millions of tons of hem in
order to redress our carbon footprint we
need to do it as soon as we possibly can
ideally we need to get to a state where
we become aware of the fact that this
planet that we live on isn't ours and
living on it is the wrong kind of
relationship we need to learn to live
with life instead of upon it or with the
planet instead of on it and in order to
do that we need to find a way of living
where we don't not claiming ownership
over the entire planet so basically we
need to give it back so we need to give
back the surface of the planet to the
natural world in order to have a future
this limits us with the idea that if we
give back the entirety of the natural
but yeah of the natural world to nature
we'd have no space for ourselves to live
so it runs into the problem of
generating space for ourselves
I'm proposing that we build huge
terraced pyramids two miles square at
their base and a mile tall
they'd out of a cross combination of
hemp and volcanic ash
it's an old form of concrete that the
Roma juste use apparently in France
there are old Roman bridges or they're
longer bridges but the foundations of
old Roman bridges that have got modern
bridges built on top of the Roman
foundations and have juggernauts going
over the top the hemp-based concrete we
have the ability to produce it we don't
have the willpower to produce it we have
the ability to grow enough heme all over
the world in order to reverse our
climate problems but we don't have the
will to do it at the moment we are
divided by all sorts of structures such
as money which causes complete
inequality and nation which allows us to
fear the other to such a degree that
we're willing to make guns bombs tanks
and all sorts of things that are
detrimental to all of life tell us more
about the
about the design of the pyramid city the
the basic zone is as though a pyramid
but terrorists from bottom to top each
flat surface
sorry each are bright surfaces in front
of houses and each flat surface is God's
each set of gardens overhangs the less
upright the front of houses by about 10
feet the idea is that with a four square
mile or two two miles by two miles at
its face the structures which is four
square miles of land we can generate
five square miles of gardens on our
rooftops have 60,000 homes on the
outside all facing out it's the open
countryside and inside each structure
generate 110 square miles of space with
an average ceiling height of 36 feet
each of the house units would be a 36
foot cube internally the whole of the
two-mile square is divided into 44 cubes
on the outside which allows four walls
being four foot thick between each
dwelling space the reason before for
thick laws is that you have insulation
from sound so it doesn't matter what
your neighbors doing you'll never hear
it and also for the infrastructure of a
building each house unit being a 36 foot
tube would have its infrastructure on
its floor its ceiling and on the three
internal walls the external world would
be passive solar glass so the light that
comes into our house will light our
house at the same time we generate
energy
inside the structure on the normal
ground we suffer from their heaving and
shifting of the ground it moves all over
the place any infrastructure we put on
the ground is liable to get damaged by
the way that the ground moves inside a
structure that I'm proposing because
it's a man-made structure and we can
make it so that it is stable digging
down to healthy foundations only
building them in places suitable we'll
be able to have
I don't hide it what the right word is
if every footstep we take uses our body
weight to pump water up in the structure
then everywhere we go we'll be
generating energy if we can recycle our
every out breath so our moisture rich
carbon dioxide rich warm air that we
breathe out can travel up in the air
flows of the structure to the top
a mile high will have a condensing cone
that would take out the moisture drop
the cold air straight back down the
center of the structure turning turbines
on its way to of the fires of Industry
the fires of Industry will take out any
pathogens in the air that as we recycle
it it'll also increase the amount of
carbon in the air we are recycling the
fires of Industry can be run on our
waste materials so any green waste or
any fun expression that we produce
where we produce it on whichever floor
of the structure we're on it has
potential kinetic energy that can be
reabsorbed by the structure on its way
between us depositing it and it reaching
processing we process it from methane
and alcohol which give us the fuels for
the fires of Industry
inside the structures we generate our
own light if you control the light and
the temperature you control the season
so in our farms inside the structure
we'll be able to have every season of
the year every month of the year we'll
be able to have everything that grows
everywhere in the world locally produced
an in constant fruition as somebody once
said man spends most of his time trying
to get from A to B
wouldn't it be a much more sensible
thing to make a the place to be so how
can we live in a sustainable environment
and this is what I'm talking about is a
way of supporting all of life so man has
claimed this world as his we've said
this is my planet whereas it belongs to
all of life equally so for men to take
it and acting the detriment of all of
life is negating from our own future to
poison the rain to poison the air to
poison the sea poison the land doesn't
actually bode for a decent future at all
so at some point I've got to take
responsibility for my actions
apparently when man grows up he's
supposed to become independent
self-reliant and responsible well at the
moment I depend on the natural world I
rely on the natural world and I'm
responsible for damaging it pretty much
destroying it with my every action I
need to change that in order to grow up
so to become independent and self
aligned I need to be able to produce my
own air so recycle air
I know that plant life when it's in
daylight will take carbon dioxide out of
the air and replace it with oxygen so if
all my farms inside the structure a
given of carbon dioxide rich air they
will process plenty of carbon dioxide
and turn it into oxygen for the housing
part of our structure for the living
part of our structure if all of our
entertainment recreation of all of our
needs are actually dealt with within
these structures then we get rid of
drought famine and flood from the
natural world
well we're no longer reliant on the
natural world we've become independent
of it and therefore natural fluctuations
in the weather in the climate won't
affect us so we want you to go to war
because we're lacking in this or lacking
in that what we'll have is we'll have a
situation where everybody's got
everything but if we go down the lines
of ownership like we go at the moment
and we try to control each other with it
and own it and buy it and sell it then
we'll end up in the same problem we'll
end up with a an inequality that will
lead to problems
got Harvey spider at home
so most of our problems that were caused
at the moment through inequality we have
a hierarchical system that
basically there's a bunch of control
freaks which house humans seem to be a
bunch of control freaks but we don't
admit the fact that we're control freaks
and we inflict our control upon
everything else but at some point we've
got to separate ourselves from
everything else and find our own way of
living so that man's world and the
natural world can become two separate
places that live in harmony side-by-side
and whence living in these structures
there's no problem with going out it's
the countryside go for a walk go and
enjoy it but we shouldn't be taking life
from it if in our structures we've got
aquariums salt water and fresh water we
don't need to fish in the sea anymore or
produce our own fish so we can clean the
Seas up detoxify them learn the skill
set that is needed to clean up the
planet and to clean up our environmental
mess build the toolset that is needed to
clean it up and find that way of living
in harmony with each other if we're all
on the same side working towards the
same goal and we don't have hierarchy
then that would be the equivalent of
everybody being earning the same of
money if we're all earning the same
money then we can do away with money
completely because if everybody's got
the same does it matter if we're living
for the love of life and we're caring
about everybody else more than our
individual selves we will all be looked
after by everybody else and we will all
look after everybody else if we care
about the planet in the same way by
looking after the planet by making it as
healthy and vital and viable as possible
it makes our lives as healthy vital the
viable as possible
so these factory structures nobody will
live at the top
nobody will live at the bottom and
nobody lives on the corners the corners
of the structure all the way from the
top to the bottom or bottom to the top
hold vertical wind turbines the vertical
wind turbines can be put in cages so
birds can't fly into them so they won't
be harmful to avian life but situating
them on the corners of the building the
building will act like a sail and the
air will travel fast around the corners
than it does in normal straight air so
will generate energy through through
that so we've got footsteps out-breath
vertical wind turbines on the corners
it's passive solar but all of the bless
all of the frontage to the building
that's recycling of our apron all of
these things should give us plenty of
energy to do pretty much whatever we
want within reason but at the moment
we're a living where we create sterile
environments in which we sleep we
connect them together with sterile
environments such as roads and in order
to get from one sterile environment to
another sterile environment we're using
vast amounts of fossil fuels in order to
sterilize the air and the land yes so at
some point we've gotta wake up to our
habits at present become very
uncomfortable with them and start
working towards making a change
hemp seems to have the answers to most
of it
the
a bunch of people that smoke a lot of
pot aren't going to go to war but you
don't have to smoke pot you know it's
not about having lots of pot to smoke
even though some of us like to smoke pot
it's about the ability to fix a large
amount of harm very quickly yeah we then
being able to use that as a construction
material laughing yeah yeah the idea of
drilling a hole and expending vast
amounts of energy pumping carbon down a
hole in order to fix the carbon by
putting it into the ground and actually
revitalize the soil at the same time
right yeah right here guys I am provide
you with a consequence free yeah you can
go up to a piece of land that's got very
little fertility and grow hemp on it and
by the end of you're growing hemp on it
it will have a lot more fertility and
vitality in the soil so yeah it
generates a healthier planet the
illegality of hemp was based on the
paper industry and land right landowners
reefer madness like land owners owning
vast amounts of forestry and not having
a way of making an income from it even
though it was inferior products so they
came up with inferior paper made hemp
illegal because paper used to be made
from hemp clothes used to be made from
him the British Empire was built on him
without the rigging for the ships
without the sails without the the ropes
this country would have never been able
to get to where it got to
so at some point hemp built the British
Empire but at some point the British
turned its back on him and made it
illegal but that illegality has led to
all sorts of crimes and it would be a
really good idea if we got rid of the
crimes I'm afraid I have a a believer in
the fact that 13 points where the heroin
and Afghanistan should cost 13 pence in
London not three hundred quid and it's
that inequality that black-marketing the
profit-making
that causes the problems that we've got
as far as drug-related crimes go if you
can walk in the sames breeze and buy a
day's fix for 13 P who would care if
you're a junkie what effect would you
have on anybody else you would affect
yourself you wouldn't go around stealing
for it you wouldn't eat it so a lot of
the time our legalities our laws
actually stop us from doing anything
that's sensible and vital for us I can
see growing vast quantities of hemp is
the only way we're going to have a
future
we're gonna have to start really soon
every front gun every back garden every
bit of public ground every space that's
not at present utilized by nature itself
because we'll leave the woodlands we'll
leave them leave the natural land as
much as you can leave natural but that
which we're taking up for our
entertainment and recreation kicking a
bladder full of air around a field or
something like that turn it to him for a
few years if in five years or if in four
years our daily we can grow let's say 50
million tons of him or hemp fiber will
have taken 50 million tons of carbon
from the atmosphere and started to
reverse our carbon footprint or carbon
problems if we don't over the near
future within within our lifetimes
climate will reach well it will be
runaway climate change will reach the
point where the methane beds and
everything else will blow up and we went
a future at all so the choice is do we
want a future that has no money no
hierarchy where so long as you're not
acting in a manner that's detrimental to
anybody else or anything else you can do
pretty much whatever you want where the
average working week is about two or
three hours rather than anymore and
we're
as a for instance you want to go on
holiday to a foreign country going by
wind power is going to take you a month
to get there what would it matter if it
takes you a month at the moment we're in
a rush you've got to get there and back
because you've got to be at work because
you've got to work the 40 or 60 hours of
doing whatever you're doing to the
detriment of the world in order to be
able to have a recreational time a
recreation in order to rebuild yourself
to the point where you can sustain or
survive another period of time where
you're doing something this recklessly
or a little bit to the veteran
environment Italy it doesn't make sense
we're living in a world it's so screwed
up that unless we wake up to it and we
start to get uncomfortable with it we're
going to destroy the future of
everything we say we love and to me
that's a problem
this guy called Darwin and a guy called
Rumble yeah and a guy called Rumble came
up with this wonderful idea
cooperative anticipates now cooperative
interdependence means that the my
aircraft feeds the trees there i pref
means me yet we've got this relationship
so I've got relationship of the trees
the waters in my blood is the same as
the water in the rain cycle I've got a
relationship I've got a relationship for
the whole of the planet that I live on
the food I eat is the mineral Kingdom is
the land that it grows on if I toxifying
poison the whole of the planet for a
short-term gain i'm toxifying and
poisoning myself if i poison the rains
imposing the water I drink my poison the
air I breathe I'm poisoning all of it so
how is it that my short-term financial
gain can be worth throwing away my
long-term environmental future
look at Rumble look at the fact that
we're actually together well we are all
as you say we're all one
at the moment we're a parasitic organism
that's dividing its host planet of its
ability at support life we need to
become a symbiotic by form that's
supporting the life of its host planet
this is a mental health problem that
we're in denial of Peter self-centered
money's the money stuff we brought in so
that we can have a standing army before
we did that the people that would be in
the army would be the same people that
grow the crops that do all the other
work in society so when the two armies
met more often than not they would send
forward a champion from each side the
two people over might be colorful to
lose and the decision would be made by
those two people fighting and the two
armies would go back to whatever it was
they were doing before right when we
invented money we had the ability to
have an expandable and expendable force
a group of people that were there Jolyon
truth simply to take life and then the
army that could just take life and it
didn't matter how many you lose because
you just buy some more could go up
against the group that had to feed
themselves had to hunt together had to
do all the other bits so decide that had
the big army that had nothing else to do
could kill all of the others take over
their space and enslaved night and
that's who now runs the world the people
that have the big armies actually no
runs no I think
like you want us to delete our
promotions like really like ramus
mortium father because they are in
hundreds of souls don't get really great
just instead I'm sorry instead of
focusing your greed to in here I'm
greedy for little me transfer our
greeter out there I'm greedy to give I'm
greedy to care I'm greedy to sort this
problem out it's not greed what's where
it's plate you turn it inside out you
know in green now become ministering we
need to lift it to our heart and give
instead of being greedy to take that's
always actually the same thing you just
have you looted hunter-gathering and
once we've broken up into tribes that
were fighting each other we did the
bartering thing to be able trade with
other tribes which obviously caused more
problems
well again again facing something that
wasn't ours yeah claiming as ours and
using it to manipulate the minds of
others but you're 13 pence worth of
heroin degree 5 and somebody in
Afghanistan well climbing in any country
is worth 300 quid so if it was
completely legal and transported but
wholesale Boyd government or whatever we
live down in they want to wipe a shop
near our your heroine fix on there a man
who got into a really bad habit a micros
226 yeah 300 walls and Quinn's 900
Connie so good he was spending Apollo
back on driving recently in the illegal
black market a generating system where
he didn't see criminality as to advisor
yes no way anybody can afford those
price again
Thanks so we have an awful lot of work
related to it's probably something we're
speakers is perfectly legal and it was
only illegal to prime it or any really
care yeah if you're going to sell our
car and sell tobacco
sell drugs at the same time of course
that yeah but you shouldn't feel as
profit when people can be silent so
we're not breaking in on
you can find amazing so you said over
the the legal system to Motel Cassatt's
support of more than I was wounded Aggie
I miscarried well as a whoa it okay then
appeal night we're coming through that
we know so all of history we know I
think we know history we don't know to
be so we educate our children to
maintain from our history which is
correct
those we're comfortable but are bound
and so that my children will make a
history for including step into our
history so we can link repeat in our
famous late brilliant over no again
because we want to defeat the
comfortable place to be it we don't want
to start
Infantino what qualities
if we change the way that we live at the
moment we claim the ownership over
additional 20 hours if we can then to
give the planet back to all of life say
it was never ours in first place we made
a terrible mistake a long time ago and
since then we've been as it were living
in sin because we've been taking
something that wasn't ours and using it
to the detriment of all of life